https://www.aafmaa.com/about/privacy-policy

Learn
Call Us Today!
Complimentary Portfolio Review
Determine your ideal investment strategy with a complimentary Investment Portfolio review.
Benefits of Membership
Personal attention, fully committed to you and your family for life
Effective Date: 1 January 2016
This Online Privacy Policy applies to AAFMAA website. For the Member Privacy please go to the following link: aafmaa.com/memberprivacypolicy
The www.aafmaa.com website is operated by the American Armed Forces Mutual Aid Association (“AAFMAA”) (referred to as “we, our, us”). This Privacy Policy applies to information submitted and collected on www.aafmaa.com and any other website offered by us which references or links to this Privacy Policy (each a “Site” and together the “Sites”). Your use of our Sites reflects your acceptance of this Privacy Policy. If you disagree with any portion of this Privacy Policy, your sole remedy is to immediately discontinue using the Sites.
For U.S. account holders and visitors to this Site, we will use and share any information that we collect from or about you in accordance with our Consumer Privacy Notice, which provides choices in the use and sharing of information.
1. Types of information we collect from you.
“Personal information” is data that can be used to uniquely identify or contact a single person. Personal information we collect may include:
Your name, mailing address, phone number, email address, birth date, Social Security Number, passport number, driver’s license number, military records, payment information, financial information (such as assets, income, account balances), health information, and similar information relating to your spouse and children
We may also ask for additional information such as your gender, occupation, and other preferences.
We obtain personal information from and about you:
That you provide, or authorize us to collect.
About your transactions with us.
Provided by consumer reporting agencies or government agencies.
For example, we collect personal information when you:
Apply for or obtain a product or service from us.
Register to access the Member Center.
Make payments.
Ask to have a representative contact you or request technical support.
By initiating any activity or transaction with us that uses payment information, you consent to providing your payment information to us and our service providers processing the transaction to the extent required to provide the payment services to you.
When we combine the information we receive from third parties (such as consumer reporting agencies) with information we collect through the Sites, we will apply this Privacy Policy to any personal information received, unless we have disclosed otherwise.
Back to top
2. Why we collect your personal information.
We collect and use personal information to provide, administer and underwrite insurance products and to provide financial services to you and your family. We use your personal information to process your claims, verify transactions, provide billing, enhance your customer experience, and offer you our services and products. We collect and use your personal information to communicate with you about our products and services and to administer our Sites, products and services, and manage, protect and improve them.
Back to top
3. We also collect cookie and traffic data.
Whenever you visit or interact with a Site, we, as well as our service providers, may use assorted technologies that automatically or passively collect information about how a Site is accessed and used. We refer to this information as traffic data.
Traffic data may include, but is not limited to: browser type, device type used to access the Site (i.e., computer or mobile device), unique number assigned to identify such device, operating system, application version, click path taken through the Site, your use of features or applications on a Site, and other publicly available information.
The site also uses Google Analytics Advertising features in order to improve User Experience. Advertising features include: Re-marketing with Google Analytics; Google Display Network Impression Reporting; Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting; Integrated services that require Google Analytics to collect data via advertising cookies and identifiers.
Technologies we use on the Sites to collect traffic data, include but are not limited to: cookies (data files placed on your computer or other devices used to access a Site), mobile analytics software and pixel tags (transparent graphic image, sometimes called a web beacon or tracking beacon, placed on a web page or in an email, which indicates that a page or email has been viewed). We, or our vendors, may place cookies or similar files on your computer or other devices used to access a Site for security purposes, to facilitate Site navigation and to personalize your experience while visiting our Sites (such as allowing us to select which content is most likely to appeal to you based on your location). A pixel tag may tell your browser to get content from another server. This information helps us analyze our Sites and improve our Sites, products and services. Traffic data is generally non-identifying, but if we associate it with you as an identifiable person, we will treat it as personal information.
To learn how you may be able to reduce the number of cookies you receive from us, or delete cookies that have already been installed in your browser’s cookie folder, please refer to your browser’s help menu or other instructions related to your browser. If you do disable or opt out of receiving cookies, please be aware that some features and services on our Sites may not work as intended and you may not have access to all of the services and features we may offer.
You can use Google’s Ads Settings to manage the Google ads you see and opt out of Ads Personalization. Even if you opt out of Ads Personalization, you may still see ads based on factors such as your general location derived from your IP address, your browser type, and your search terms.
Back to top
4. To protect the confidentiality and security of your non-public, personal information we:
Maintain, monitor and update physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect personal information.
Use security and encryption methods to help prevent data breaches and unauthorized disclosure of personal information.
Restrict access to personal information to necessary personnel only.
Although guaranteed security does not exist on the Internet or offline, we make commercially reasonable efforts to handle such information consistent with this Privacy Policy and applicable laws. Due to the design of the Internet and other factors outside our control, we cannot guarantee that communications between you and our servers will be free from unauthorized access by third parties.
Back to top
5. We disclose information to affiliates and non-affiliated third parties.
We share information with affiliates and non-affiliated companies to manage business as permitted or required by law. For example, we may share information to help file claims on insurance policies for the deceased, or we may contract with non-affiliated third parties to administer our products and services to include underwriting, banking, mail and data processing. We only share information necessary for the contracted services. For CAP loans, we may disclose personal information to consumer reporting or collection agencies. AAFMAA may also disclose personal information to government agencies and regulatory organizations as permitted or required by law.
We never rent or sell any personal information to marketers outside AAFMAA.
For U.S. account holders and visitors to this Site, we will use and share any information that we collect from or about you in accordance with our Consumer Privacy Notice, which provides choices in the use and sharing of information.
We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in connection with a sale, merger, consolidation, change in control, transfer of assets, reorganization or liquidation of our business. We reserve the right to disclose any personal information as needed if that information is requested by law enforcement agencies or if we are required to do so by law, treaty, regulation, subpoena, court order, or by a government entity. We also may disclose your personal information to third parties if we have reason to believe that disclosing such information is necessary to conduct investigations of possible breaches of law, to cooperate in any legal investigation, or to identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may be violating any agreement with us or our Terms and Conditions of Use.
If you request services via a mobile device, your request will be transmitted via your mobile carrier’s network and your carrier may have access to it. Consult your carrier’s privacy policy for additional information.
Back to top
6. We disclose information about former Members.
AAFMAA may disclose some or all of a former Member’s personal information to government agencies, consultants and self-regulatory organizations when permitted or required by law, such as required to file abandoned property reports, compliance with subpoenas and other official requests. We may report the payment history of CAP loans to consumer reporting agencies.
Back to top
7. Medical information is disclosed only to those needing your information to process insurance applications or claims.
We provide necessary information and test results to a paramedic and/or physician for insurance underwriting. Medical information may be shared with MIB, Inc., if specifically authorized on the insurance application, as part of the underwriting process.
Back to top
8. How to opt-out and change your personal information.
If you no longer wish to receive our promotional communications, contact us by email to be removed from our lists. Be sure to include any contact information that you want removed from our promotional contacts list, including physical addresses, phone numbers, and email addresses (if you use more than one email address, send your opt-out email from each of your email addresses). If you receive any online newsletter or similar promotional email communication from us, you will always be given the option to “unsubscribe” from receiving further email communications from us at any time. Your option not to receive promotional and marketing material will not preclude us from corresponding with you, by email or otherwise, regarding your existing or past business relationships with us (e.g., any purchase of our products or use of our services, or responses to requests for information you pose to us either through use of a Site or by other means), and will not preclude us from accessing and viewing your personal information in the course of maintaining and improving our Sites and our services.
If you want to opt-out of receiving promotional communications from us, or if your personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code, phone, email or postal address), you may correct, update or delete/deactivate your personally identifiable information at any time by sending an email to policyservices@aafmaa.com. If you are a registered Member, you may be able to log into your account and update some of your personal information. Note that if you have a separate agreement with us or our affiliates, you should also check the notice provisions in that agreement and update us or our affiliates if any contact information changes according to the notice provisions in that agreement. Your notifying policyservices@aafmaa.com of any personal information changes will not serve as notice under any separate agreement you may have with us or our affiliates.
Back to top
9. Links to third-party sites.
Our Sites may contain links to other sites that may be of interest to our users. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each website to which we may link that may collect personal information. You are responsible for any information or content you post using a third-party social networking platform, such as Facebook or Twitter, and using such platforms in a manner consistent with the privacy policy and other terms and conditions applicable to such platforms.
Back to top
10. How we respond to do-not-track requests and use of third-party tracking.
Unless your browser settings are configured to make your online activities and publicly available information about your online activities (such as traffic data described above) invisible to usage analytics tools, we do not presently have the capability to omit you from usage analytics to the extent your browser only sends us a “do not track” message and does not otherwise screen you from tracking without any action on our part.
Third parties, other than our vendors (such as our website analytics provider), do not have authorization from us to track which websites you visited prior and after visiting our Sites. That said, we cannot control third party tracking and there may be some third party tracking that occurs without our knowledge or consent.
Back to top
11. Children.
The Sites are not intended for use by children under the age of 13, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from such children. If we learn that we have collected the personal information of such a child we will take steps to delete the information as soon as possible.
Back to top
12. Notice to residents of countries outside the United States.
We are headquartered in the United States. Personal information may be accessed by us or transferred to us in the United States or to our affiliates, business partners, or service providers elsewhere in the world. If you are located outside of the United States, be advised that any information you provide to us will be transferred to and stored in the United States and that, by submitting information to us, you explicitly authorize its transfer and storage within the United States. We will protect the privacy and security of personal information according to this Privacy Policy regardless of where it is processed or stored. For European Union (EU) residents, if you have questions regarding AAFMAA’s Privacy Policy, contact AAFMAA’s Data Privacy Officer (DPO) at secretary@aafmaa.com.
Back to top
13. Changes to this Privacy Policy.
We reserve the right to change or replace this Privacy Policy at our sole discretion at any time. In the event our Privacy Policy should materially change, we will generally notify our users by posting a notice of such change in a separate section of this Privacy Policy. Your continued use of any of our Sites following the posting of changes to our Privacy Policy means you accept those changes.
Back to top
14. Our Affiliates.
This privacy policy has been adopted by AAFMAA and its affiliated companies. Our affiliates include: AAFMAA Wealth Management & Trust LLC., and AAFMAA Mortgage Services LLC.
Back to top
15. Contact Us.
If you have questions regarding AAFMAA’s Privacy Policy, contact AAFMAA’s Secretary at 888-976-3712, ext. 4602 or email secretary@aafmaa.com.
Let's Talk
Contact a Representative
1-800-522-5221
Mon - Fri 8:30AM - 5:30PM ET
(Insurance Sales until 7:00PM)
Send us a Question
Contact Us
AAFMAA
About Us
Learn
FAQs
Contact
Make a Payment
Trust Services
Contact a Representative:
1-800-522-5221
Facebook
LinkedIn
Twitter
Youtube
Rss Feed
AAFMAA
About Us
Forms
Contact a Representative:
1-800-522-5221
Facebook
LinkedIn
Twitter
Youtube
Rss Feed
Copyright 2020 American Armed Forces Mutual Aid Association. 102 Sheridan Avenue, Ft. Myer, VA 22211-1110
The U.S. Government does not sanction, recommend or encourage the sale of these life insurance products. Subsidized life insurance may be available from the Federal Government.
Privacy Policy |
Terms & Conditions |
Social Security
Number Policy |
Site Map
AAFMAA Wealth Management & Trust
Financial Planning, Investment Management, and Trust Services provided by AAFMAA Wealth Management
& Trust, a North Carolina Limited Liability Company wholly owned by AAFMAA. Physical address:
639 Executive Place, Suite 200, Fayetteville, NC 28305.
Information provided by AAFMAA Wealth Management & Trust LLC is not intended to be tax or legal advice. Nothing contained in this communication should be interpreted as such. We encourage you to seek guidance from your tax or legal advisor. Past performance does not guarantee future results.
AAFMAA Wealth Managment Facebook
AAFMAA Wealth Managment LinkedIn
AAFMAA Wealth Managment Instagram
Privacy Policy
AAFMAA Mortgage Services LLC
Mortgage services provided by AAFMAA Mortgage Services LLC, an Equal Housing Lender and a wholly-owned subsidiary of AAFMAA. AAFMAA Mortgage Services LLC is only available for the financing of residential property in the states listed on our Legal & Licensing page. All loans are subject to credit approval. Physical address: 1 Copley Pkwy, Suite 420, Morrisville, NC 27560. Lender NMLS: 1423968
https://www.nmlsconsumeraccess.org/
LinkedIn
AAFMAA Mortgage Services LLC Facebook
AAFMAA Mortgage Services LLC Twitter
Disclaimer |
Legal & Licensing |
Privacy Policy |
Fair Lending Notice |
